

SAN DIEGO, CA | RELOCATING TO LOS ANGELES 858-649-0040 GARY@GARYNORMAN.ME

PORTFOLIO: WWW.GARYNORMAN.ME

SUMMARY

MULTIFACETED, CREATIVE PROBLEM SOLVER WITH OVER SIX YEARS OF EXPERIENCE IN DIGITAL DESIGN & WEB DEVELOPMENT, VIDEO & AUDIO PRODUCTION, AND MANAGEMENT. VISUAL DESIGNER AND MANAGER WHO LEVERAGES EXCELLENT COMMUNICATION, INTERPERSONAL AND CLIENT MANAGEMENT SKILLS TO PRODUCE OUTSTANDING VISUAL PRODUCTS THAT HAVE A RETURN ON THEIR INVESTMENT. DEDICATED TO LEARNING, EVALUATING AND APPLYING NEW TECHNOLOGIES IN ORDER TO ENHANCE CONTENT, FUNCTIONALITY AND OVERALL USABILITY. ALWAYS LOOKING AT THE BIG PICTURE FIRST.

WORK EXPERIENCE

COUNTRY REBEL CREATIVE TEAM CONTENT MANAGER | JUL. 2016 - PRESENT

- BUILT OUT A NEW VIDEO AND AUDIO PRODUCTION DEPARTMENT WITHIN THE COMPANY AND MANAGED A TEAM OF EDITORS
 AND MOTION GRAPHIC DESIGNERS THROUGH MULTIPLE CREATIVE PROJECTS
- LEAD ALL ASPECTS OF PRODUCTION FROM PRE-PRODUCTION TO POST-PRODUCTION AND PUBLISHING OF A 4 DAY, 32 ARTIST, 120 SONG, ACOUSTIC RECORDING SESSION OUT OF STATE
- PRODUCED, DIRECTED, AND EDITED ACOUSTIC PERFORMANCE VIDEOS THAT HAVE GAINED OVER 80 MILLION VIEWS ON FACEBOOK AND YOUTUBE COMBINED
- GREW A YOUTUBE CHANNEL WITH ACOUSTIC MUSIC SESSION CONTENT TO 168K+ SUBSCRIBERS
- HELPED MANAGE THE OVERALL ECOSYSTEM OF COMPANY MAC COMPUTERS (IT), NICHE WEBSITES AND FACEBOOK GROUPS,
 DIGITAL CREATIVE ASSETS AND WORKFLOWS
- DESIGNED MEDIA KITS, PUT TOGETHER RFPS FOR MUSICAL EVENT ADVERTISEMENT PACKAGES AND CREATED SUPPORTING SOCIAL MEDIA ARTWORK FOR ROCK AND ROLL AND COUNTRY MUSIC ARTISTS LIKE GAVIN DEGRAW AND LYNYRD SKYNYRD
- COLLABORATED WITH A WRITER OF ANOTHER NICHE IN THE COMPANY AND NARRATED SHORT, ANIMATED, INFORMATIONAL VIDEOS THAT REACHED OVER 1 MILLION VIEWS ON YOUTUBE.

MIVA.COM E-COMMERCE WEB DEVELOPER | APR. 2015 - JAN. 2016

- DEVELOPED AND PRESENTED CUSTOM SOLUTIONS FOR ECOMMERCE WEBSITES USING MIVA MERCHANT'S SAAS SYSTEM
- ADVISED CLIENTS ABOUT SEO, SOCIAL MEDIA AND ECOMMERCE BEST PRACTICES
- INTERACTED WITH CLIENTS DIRECTLY THROUGH KAYAKO'S SUPPORT SOFTWARE
- DEVELOPED FEATURES TO SMART DESIGN TEMPLATES WHICH POSITIVELY INCREASED THE USER EXPERIENCE

BR4SS INC. INDEPENDENT WEB CONTRACTOR & PRODUCTION DESIGNER | OCT. 2014 - JUL. 2016

- BUILT A RESPONSIVE, CUSTOM THEMED E-COMMERCE WEBSITE UTILIZING WORDPRESS CMS AND WOOCOMMERCE
- PLAYED AN INTEGRAL ROLE IN RE-DEFINING THE OVERALL LOOK AND FEEL OF THE BRAND
- CREATED WEB AND PRINT MATERIALS USED FOR SOCIAL MEDIA MARKETING AND DISTRIBUTOR ACQUISITION

U.S. NAVY QUARTERMASTER SECOND CLASS PETTY OFFICER | OCT. 2007 - OCT. 2011

- MARINE NAVIGATION AND COMMISSIONING OF A 2.5 BILLION DOLLAR AMPHIBIOUS ASSAULT SHIP. (LHD-8 USS MAKIN ISLAND)
- WORK CENTER SUPERVISOR MANAGING 10 YOUNGER, LESS EXPERIENCED SAILORS
- DEVELOPED SELF-DISCIPLINE, RESPONSIBILITY, PATIENCE, AND A CAN-DO ATTITUDE

EDUCATION

THE ART INSTITUTE OF CALIFORNIA - SAN DIEGO | 2015

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE | WEB DESIGN AND INTERACTIVE MEDIA
MAC OS | WEB DEVELOPMENT | VIDEO PRODUCTION | MOTION GRAPHICS | GRAPHIC DESIGN
PHOTOGRAPHY | AUDIO PRODUCTION